<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DPSN Home on Data Protection Scholars Network</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/</link><description>Recent content in DPSN Home on Data Protection Scholars Network</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>the authors</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dataprotectionscholars.network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DPSN Launch at CPDP 2022</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp2022/</guid><description>After its first online meet-up in January 2022 on International Data Protection Day that brought together more than 150 data protection law scholars from all over the world, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) will have its official launch in-person at CPDP2022!
The DPSN is a network that aims at facilitating academic exchanges between international researchers working in the field of data protection law, in Europe and beyond. Open to all researchers, it focuses on supporting exchanges between early-stage academics from all over Europe; encouraging diversity; advancing the bridges between data protection scholarship of all continents; promoting the study of data protection law in Europe and beyond.</description></item><item><title>Data Protection Day Event 2022 - Summary</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/data-protection-day-event/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/data-protection-day-event/</guid><description>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the Data Protection Day, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network organised the first ever international quick meet-up of data protection law researchers. The event brought together more than 150 data protection law scholars from all over the world.
27 speakers, divided into two parallel sessions, presented in 3 slides and 5 minutes their current work, be it a developing PhD, an interesting master thesis, a collection of educational material, an upcoming promising paper or a brand-new project.</description></item><item><title>Final programme for our online event on the international Data Protection Day!</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event28012022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event28012022/</guid><description>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the international Data Protection Day, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network organises the first ever international quick meet-up of data protection law researchers. The event will take place online, at 13:00-15:10 Brussels time.
Format/What to expect Speakers were selected through a call for abstracts for very short presentations that the Network launched back in December 2021. Data protection law scholars of all levels of seniority will present in 3 slides and 5 minutes their current work, be it a developing PhD, an interesting master thesis, an upcoming promising paper or a brand-new project.</description></item><item><title>DPSN Event on International Data Protection Day</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event_on_int_dp_day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event_on_int_dp_day/</guid><description>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the international Data Protection Day, the DPSN will organise the first ever international quick meet-up of data protection law researchers.
We want to create a platform for people to get to know each other’s work better. With this in mind, we are calling for expressions of interest to do very short presentations of your research – be it your developing PhD, interesting master thesis, upcoming promising paper or brand new project.</description></item><item><title>The DPSN at CPDP LatAm 2021</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp_latam_panel2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp_latam_panel2021/</guid><description>We are very glad to participate with a panel to the Conference CPDP LatAm 2021 taking place from July 14th to 16th 2021. The panel takes place on July 16th (Room 3), 10:00-11:30 BRT/ 16:00-17:30 CEST. We hope to meet many of you there!
Panel: Data protection law scholars of the world, unite! (in little groups?) Towards a global data protection network?
In light of the growing importance of data protection laws across the world, there is an increased need for robust international expert networks in the field.</description></item><item><title>TILTing 2021</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/tilting2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/tilting2021/</guid><description>We are very glad to participate to the Conference TILTing Perspectives 2021: Regulating in Times of Crisis taking place from May 19th to 21st 2021. We thank the organisers for their support in promoting the setting up of this Network, and hope to meet many of you there.</description></item><item><title>About the Network</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/steering_and_management_committees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/steering_and_management_committees/</guid><description>The daily management of the Data Protection Law Scholars Network is currently led by the following Steering Committee:
Gloria González Fuster, Research Professor, Vrije Universiteit Brussel Jef Ausloos, Postdoctoral Researcher, Universiteit van Amsterdam Kristina Irion, Associate Professor, Universiteit van Amsterdam Eleni Kosta, Professor of Technology Law and Human Rights, Tilburg University Lee A Bygrave, Professor, University of Oslo Franziska Boehm, Professor, Leibniz-Institute for Information Infrastructure in Karlsruhe (FIZ) and the Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) Orla Lynskey, Associate Professor, London School of Economics Michael Veale, Lecturer in Digital Rights and Regulation, University College London The Management Committee coordinating the Network is composed of:</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/contact/</guid><description>Keep in touch by signing up here. Contact us at dpsn@posteo.eu.</description></item><item><title>Useful DP Links</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/useful/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/useful/</guid><description>General European Commission &amp;ndash; Data protection https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en
Council of Europe Data Protection website
Global Privacy Assembly (GPA) https://globalprivacyassembly.org/
European Data Protection Board (EDPB) https://edpb.europa.eu/edpb_en
European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS) https://edps.europa.eu/_en
GDPR Hub https://gdprhub.eu/index.php?title=Welcome_to_GDPRhub
Centre for Intellectual Property and Information Law (CIPIL) overview of national https://www.cipil.law.cam.ac.uk/resources/european-data-protection-national-laws-current-and-historic and transnational https://www.cipil.law.cam.ac.uk/resources/pan-european-data-protection-and-e-privacy data protection instruments
Computers, Privacy &amp;amp; Data Protection (CPDP) panel videos https://www.</description></item></channel></rss>