<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Data Protection Scholars Network</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/</link><description>Recent content in News on Data Protection Scholars Network</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>the authors</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visit our DPSN Booth at the EDPS Conference 2022 in Brussels!</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn-at-edps-conference-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn-at-edps-conference-2022/</guid><description>The Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) participates with a booth at the 2022 EDPS Conference &amp;ldquo;The Future of Data Protection: Effective Enforcement in the Digital World&amp;rdquo;!
The event takes place on 16 &amp;amp; 17 June 2022 in Brussels. The venue of the EDPS conference is The Egg (Rue Barastraat, 175 1070 Brussels, Belgium) and is open to registered participants. When and where can you find our booth? We will be present both days at the riverside area of The Egg!</description></item><item><title>DPSN Launch at CPDP 2022</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp2022/</guid><description>After its first online meet-up in January 2022 on International Data Protection Day that brought together more than 150 data protection law scholars from all over the world, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) will have its official launch in-person at CPDP2022 on Monday 23 May 2022, 19:00-20:00 BXL time at Maison des Arts (Chau. de Haecht 147, 1030 Schaerbeek)! Drinks and some fingerfood will be provided.
At this event, you can expect to meet our members, including many of its Steering and Management Committee members, and network with fellow data protection scholars in an informal setting, as well as engage in an open discussion about what such a network can do for members in order to facilitate their work in the field of data protection.</description></item><item><title>Data Protection Day Event 2022 - Summary</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/data-protection-day-event/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/data-protection-day-event/</guid><description>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the Data Protection Day, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network organised the first ever international quick meet-up of data protection law researchers. The event brought together more than 150 data protection law scholars from all over the world.
27 speakers, divided into two parallel sessions, presented in 3 slides and 5 minutes their current work, be it a developing PhD, an interesting master thesis, a collection of educational material, an upcoming promising paper or a brand-new project.</description></item><item><title>Final programme for our online event on the international Data Protection Day!</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event28012022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event28012022/</guid><description>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the international Data Protection Day, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network organises the first ever international quick meet-up of data protection law researchers. The event will take place online, at 13:00-15:10 Brussels time.
Format/What to expect Speakers were selected through a call for abstracts for very short presentations that the Network launched back in December 2021. Data protection law scholars of all levels of seniority will present in 3 slides and 5 minutes their current work, be it a developing PhD, an interesting master thesis, an upcoming promising paper or a brand-new project.</description></item><item><title>DPSN Event on International Data Protection Day</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event_on_int_dp_day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event_on_int_dp_day/</guid><description>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the international Data Protection Day, the DPSN will organise the first ever international quick meet-up of data protection law researchers.
We want to create a platform for people to get to know each other’s work better. With this in mind, we are calling for expressions of interest to do very short presentations of your research – be it your developing PhD, interesting master thesis, upcoming promising paper or brand new project.</description></item><item><title>The DPSN at CPDP LatAm 2021</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp_latam_panel2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp_latam_panel2021/</guid><description>We are very glad to participate with a panel to the Conference CPDP LatAm 2021 taking place from July 14th to 16th 2021. The panel takes place on July 16th (Room 3), 10:00-11:30 BRT/ 16:00-17:30 CEST. We hope to meet many of you there!
Panel: Data protection law scholars of the world, unite! (in little groups?) Towards a global data protection network?
In light of the growing importance of data protection laws across the world, there is an increased need for robust international expert networks in the field.</description></item><item><title>TILTing 2021</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/tilting2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/tilting2021/</guid><description>We are very glad to participate to the Conference TILTing Perspectives 2021: Regulating in Times of Crisis taking place from May 19th to 21st 2021. We thank the organisers for their support in promoting the setting up of this Network, and hope to meet many of you there.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn_accessnow_study2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn_accessnow_study2022/</guid><description>The Data Protection Law Scholars Network is glad to present its first research output, a pan-European empirical study on the right to lodge a data protection complaint under the General Data Protection Regulation!
The Report &amp;lsquo;The right to lodge a data protection complaint: OK, but then what?&amp;rsquo; was issued in June 2022.
Authors: Gloria González Fuster (Law,Science, Technology &amp;amp; Society (LSTS), Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB)), Jef Ausloos (Institute for Information Law (IViR), University of Amsterdam (UvA)), Damian Bons (IViR, UvA), Lee A.</description></item></channel></rss>